Guide to the Dorothy Sarnoff papers, 1920-1998.
Sarnoff, Dorothy Papers, 1920-1998
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dorothy Sarnoff papers, 1920-1998, 1941-1984 (bulk)
3147
Dorothy Sarnoff
28.9 cubic ft.
Correspondence, photographs, scrapbooks, published material, sheet music, audio and video recordings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Material relating to Dorothy Sarnoff's personal life and careers as a Singer and Speech Consultant.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Singer, Speech Consultant, and Author
Dorothy Sarnoff was born in Brooklyn, N.Y. in 1914 and graduated in the Cornell University class of 1935. She became an accomplished singer on Broadway, television, and in Opera, starring in "The King and I" with Yul Brynner. Her performance credits include "Rosalinda," "My Darlin' Aida," "Tosca," "Magdalena," "The Ed Sullivan Show," a USO show in Germany, and Super Club Acts at the Pierre Hotel's Cotillion Room and the Americana Hotel's Bal Masque Supper Club. She founded "Speech Dynamics Inc.," a speech consultancy firm, and held speech cosmetics classes in New York City. In this capacity she aided Israeli Prime Minister Menachem Begin with a public speaking engagement and in 1980 she assisted President Jimmy Carter with his State of the Union Address. Dorothy Sarnoff died on December 20, 2008, in Manhattan.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Personal items include correspondence; a 1935 Cornellian with pictures and notes; photographs of family and friends; and a notebook from a Philosophy course taken at Cornell.
Material relating to her singing career includes telegrams; publicity photographs and photographs of shows; a dress worn at the Cotillion room; newspaper clippings; billings; contracts; scripts; victrola records; and an extensive collection of sheet music.
Material from Speech career includes books and audio cassettes by Dorothy Sarnoff; newspaper clippings; UHS, U-Matic, and VHS recordings of training courses and television appearances; "LUV letters"- correspondence thanking Ms. Sarnoff for speech services; notes on meetings with President Carter and Israeli Prime Minister Menachem Begin; memorabilia from Alan L. Bean and Skylab; a scrapbook relating to her visit to the White House; and assorted memorabilia from famous people. Books authored by Dorothy Sarnoff include Speech Can Change Your Life, Make the Most of Your Best, and Never Be Nervous Again.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Sarnoff, Dorothy.; Bean, Alan L.; Begin, Menachem, 1913-; Carter, Jimmy, 1924-; Sullivan, Ed, 1902-; Sarnoff, Dorothy. Speech can change your life.
Subjects:
Speech.; Revues.; Opera.; Speeches, addresses, etc.; Singers.; Women singers.
Places:
United States--Politics and government--1977-1981.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Sheet music.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Personal, 1927-1970
Correspondence, Financial Documents, Material related to Dorothy Sarnoff's Education, Photographs
Series II. Singing Career, 1933-1971
Correspondence, Contracts, Awards, Programs, Billings, Publicity Material, Sheet Music and Scripts, Recordings, Photographs and Art, Miscellany
Series III. Speech Career, 1957-1998
Correspondence, Clippings, Photographs, Administrative and Advertising Material, Recordings, Books and Cassettes, Memorabilia from Famous People, Miscellany
Series IV. Scrapbooks, 1940-1959
Scrapbooks of Newspaper Clippings
Series V. Clippings, 1930-1979
Newspaper and Magazine Articles about Dorothy Sarnoff
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Personal
  - A. Correspondence
    - Personal Correspondence, 1934-1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Arabanel, Lina (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Aronson, Shepard Gerard (Shep) (Box 1, Folder 1)
        17 items
      - Sarnoff, Dorothy (Signed "Bubbelie") (Box 1, Folder 1)
        To Parents from Paris
      - Sarnoff, Dorothy (Signed "Dot") (Box 1, Folder 1)
        To Parents from Quebec
      - Sarnoff, Dr. and Mrs. Jacob (Box 1, Folder 1)
        Wedding Announcement - Dorothy and Shep
    - Wedding Announcement, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Benesch, Alfred A. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Bill (Box 1, Folder 2)
        To Mrs. Sarnoff
      - Bill (different from above) (Box 1, Folder 2)
        To "Dear Dad",
      - Bodie (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Burghauvy(?), H. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Busch, Fritz (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Ed (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Gail (?) (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Green, Abel (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Korngold, Erich Wolfgang (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Martin, Mary (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Norman (Box 1, Folder 2)
        To Belle (Dorothy's Mother)
      - Peerce, Jan (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Robards, Bill (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Sarnoff, Dorothy (Box 1, Folder 2)
        To Mrs. Anna Roossin, Dorothy's Grandmother
      - Sarnoff, Jacob (Signed "Jack") (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Shep (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Soph (Box 1, Folder 2)
        To Belle
      - Steinbrink, Meier (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Barker, W.T. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Berman, Harry (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Helman, Max (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Hudson, H. Lewis (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Re: Distinguished Service Award, 1947
      - Kannual (?) Gertrude B. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Kilpatrick, John Reed (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Kirsch, Marvin (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Love, Robert A. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Neubert, H. Norman (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Ross, I. Arnold (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Shaw, Florence B. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Traub, Solomon (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Beldock, George J. (Box 1, Folder 4)
        Two Items
      - Bortin, David (signed "Dave") (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Boucher, Elin (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Boyce, Alfred (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Brewer, R. Selden (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Burton, Kenneth (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Crawford, Cheryl (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Dispeker, Thea (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Edwards, Ralph (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Freedley, Vinton (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Gardner, Edith L (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Gillett, Bill (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Goldschmidt, Nicholas (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Grossinger, Jennie (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Henry, Robert S. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Johnson, Harriett (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Judson, Arthur (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Melchior, Lauritz (signed "Kleinchen Melchior) (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Resta, Francis E. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Robinson, Stillman W. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Sarnoff, David (signed "D.S.") (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Schecter, S. H. (Signed "Sam") (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Schroeder, Marion (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Shep (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Short, W.A. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Smith, Edward G. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Standish, Louis J., Jr. (signed "Lou") (Box 1, Folder 4)
        To Dr. Shepard G. Aronson
      - Teichman, Howard (Box 1, Folder 4)
        Re: Youth Oscar Award
      - Wallenstein, Alfred (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Wecker, Karl (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Wentworth, Philip (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Wenzel, Fr. Damien A., O.F.M. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - "Your old..."[unsigned] (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Baer, Louise (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Beldock, George J. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Feder, Nathan (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Kreutzer, S. Stanley (signed "Stan") (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Lees, Lowell (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Perkell, Murray (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Peters, Frances E. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Schwaeber, Martin (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Letterhead of Arkansas State Symphony Association
    - Personal Correspondence, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - "Lulu"(?) (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Brigham, Barbara (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Duddy, Lyn (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Hammerstein, Dorothy (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Hammerstein, Oscar, II (signed "Oscar") (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Jean (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Keener, J.W. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Lewine, Richard (signed "Dick") (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Manulis, Martin (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Mayer, Cecile Lehman (Mrs. Edgar) (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Maynard (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Rodgers, Dorothy (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Sarnoff, Charlotte (Mrs. Stanley J.) (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Tuttle, Willson M. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Whalen, Grover A. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Williams, Maynard Owen (signed "Maynard") (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - "Marta and Sam" (Box 1, Folder 7)
        Includes Cartoon drawing of Sam in newspaper shorts
      - Aronson, Dr. Henry (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Beldock, George J. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Brynner, Yul (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - DeBarger, Mary Steinman (Mrs. Charles F.) (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Drewes, Frederick W. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Edwina (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Felt, Elaine (Esther Edelman) (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Francl, Mrs. A. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Freeman, Alwyn W. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Frey, Leonard (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Gillespie, Robert (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Hall, John J. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Hammond, Hazel (Mrs. W. S.) (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Hopper, Hedda (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Krupyak, Joe (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Lally, Edward M. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - McMahon, Paul (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Moreau, Betty (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Rodgers, Richard (signed "Dick") (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Rosenthal, Jackie (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Rudd, Grace H. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Sarnoff, Dorothy (Box 1, Folder 7)
        To Mr. Alfred Lichtenstein (Returned to sender)
      - Schwartz, Etta (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Shepherd, George (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Shryock, Jean (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1953-1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - "Dot and Milt" (Box 1, Folder 8)
        Father's Day card
        To "Dearest Dad"
      - "Molfke(?), Ruth (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Alper, Nina (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Elkes, Albert Z. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Ferrer, Jose (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Goday, Happy (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Golden, John (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Greene, Edwin K. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Malone, George W. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - McKay, Mrs. Hugh D. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Sarnoff, David (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Sarnoff, David (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Sarnoff, Jacob (Box 1, Folder 8)
        To Mr. Huttner
      - Savell, Jaris (?) (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Weisman, Al (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wedding Invitation, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Raymond, Mike and Billie (Box 1, Folder 11)
        Handwritten, to Dorothy's and Milton's wedding...
        "Dear Doctor"
    - Personal Correspondence undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Balinth, Tiberiu S. (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Chillingsworth (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Clurman, D. (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Epstein, Rae (Mrs. Max) (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Farley, Johnny (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Ferguson, Mrs. Donald (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Gebad (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Goodman, Mrs. Morris (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Grant, Julia K. (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Lee, Baayork (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - McVeigh, Blake (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Plaut, Gloria (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Sarnoff, Dr. Jacob (signed "Jack") (Box 1, Folder 9)
        3 letters
      - Shep (Box 1, Folder 9)
        12 items
      - Sullivan, Vernieca (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - West, Isabel White (Mrs. Francis, Jr.) (Box 1, Folder 9)
        2 letters
      - Wilmot, Vic (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Christmas Card Lists, Address Book (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Personal - Christmas Card Lists, 1940's-1950's (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - B. Financial
    - Financial documents unrelated to career (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - C. Education
    - Cortelyou Road School Graduation Program, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - High School Report Cards, 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - High School Diploma from Berkeley Institute, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Certificate of membership in Alpha Epsilon Phi Fraternity, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Notebook from Philosophy Course at Cornell, ca. 1933 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Cornellian with notes and inserted pictures, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Berkeley Institute Alumnae Register, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - D. Photographs
    - Dorothy Sarnoff's mother, ca. 1920, Oversized (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Dorothy Sarnoff Childhood, ca. 1920-1924 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Dorothy Sarnoff Teenage Years, ca. 1927-1932 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous personal photographs, ca. 1930-1939 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Wedding photograph, 1937, Oversized (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Personal Photographs - Shep in WWII, ca. 1940-1949 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous personal photographs, ca. 1940-1949 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous personal photographs, ca. 1940-1949 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Stanley Sarnoff, 1949, Oversized (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous personal photographs, ca. 1950-1959 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous personal photographs, ca. 1950-1959 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Milton H. Raymond ca. 1957 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Milton H. Raymond negative, ca. 1957 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Milton H. Raymond's hand, 1957, Oversized (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Personal Photographs, ca. 1960-1969 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - 3 photographs of Stanley Sarnoff: Confirmation, Yearbook, Adulthood (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - 3 photographs of Shepard Aronson: Childhood, Cornell yearbook, Army (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous personal photographs (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous personal photographs (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous personal negatives (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous personal negatives (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous personal negatives (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous personal negatives (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous personal negatives (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - E. Miscellaneous
    - Miscellany (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Binder of collected recipes; California Drivers Licence, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Series II. Singing Career
  - A. Correspondence
    - Telegrams, 1938-1941 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Business Correspondence, 1941-1944 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Hearst, Siegfried (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Illingworth, Elsie (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Lester, Edwin (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Levine, Marks (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Telegrams, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Telegrams, 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Philanthropy/Awards/Engagement Correspondence, 1943-1950 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Ammerman, Gertrude (Mrs. Benjamin) (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Brunie, Henry C. (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Clark, Vernon L (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Dietz, Carl P. (Box 1, Folder 27)
        Presenting Treasury Silver Medal Award
      - Gottlober, Sigmund (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Greene, Patterson (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Kenworthy, W.E. (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Kurz, Major Phillip W. (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - McCrary, Jinx Falkenburg (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - McFarland, Frances (Mrs. W.L.) (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Michener, James A. (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Muir, Frances T. (Mrs. Malcolm) (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Business Correspondence, 1945-1947 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Telegrams, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Business Correspondence, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Brewer, R. Selden (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Lester, Edwin (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Pinkham, Eleanor (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Sarnoff, Dorothy (Box 1, Folder 23)
        Three letters
        To Edwin Lester, Re: "Magdalena"
    - Telegrams, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Business Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Beckwith, Ethel (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Fearnley, John (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Lester, Edwin (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Telegrams, 1949-1952 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Philanthropy/Awards/Engagement Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Ammerman, Gertrude (Mrs. Benjamin) (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Eichelberger, Clark M. (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Jablons, Mitchell (signed "Mike") (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Morgenthau, Henry, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Potofsky, Jacob S. (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Ridgway, Marianne (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Rogers, Adele (Mrs. Hugo E.) (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Swartz, Charles H., Brigadier General (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Waterman, Philip M. (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Weitman, Robert M. (signed "Bob") (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Business Correspondence, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Duddy, Lyn (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Hammer, Elgie B. (Mrs. Murray J.) (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Rosenbaum, Helen L (Mrs. Leon A.) (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Van Wyck, Wilfrid (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Telegrams, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Business Correspondence, 1953-1970 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - [Deane, Martha]?(illegible signature) (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Callahan, Martin C. (signed "Cal") (Box 1, Folder 26)
        Two letters
        "Dear Dorothy and Milton..."
      - Sarnoff, Stanley J. (unsigned) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Philanthropy/Awards/Engagement Correspondence, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Bergin, William E., Major General (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Borg, Madelenie (Mrs. Sidney G.) (Box 1, Folder 29)
        Presenting Certificate Of Esteem
      - Cook, William H. (signed "Bill") (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Gardiner, Eleanor (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Goldenson, Leonard H. (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Hamburger, Marilyn (Box 1, Folder 29)
        Re: Alpha Epsilon Phi National Alumnae Award
      - Kross, Anna M. (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Lane, Mrs. Morton (signed "Ruth") (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Larkin, Clifford A. (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Linderholm, Natalie W. (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Sarnoff, Dorothy (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Sonnabend, A.M. (Box 1, Folder 29)
        To Mrs. Philip Greenwood
      - Touster, Bertha (Mrs. Ben) (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Weisberg, Mrs. Philip P. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Philanthropy/Awards/Engagement Correspondence, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Eddy, Lill (Mrs. Norman) (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Goldenson, Leonard H. (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Hausman, Jack (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Lajous, Adrian (signed "Adrian") (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Mahon, (Rev.) Leo T. (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Morrison, Helen (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Mottram, Harold M. (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Raybon, Perry F. (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Robbins, Herman (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Whitehead, James W. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Philanthropy/Awards/Engagement Correspondence, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Bernstein, Leonard (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Bisgyer, Maurice (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Blumstein, Molly (Mrs. George) (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Brown, Mary (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Buckley, John R. (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Carithers, Cornelia M., M.D. (signed "Connie") (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Chayefsky, Paddy (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Hartman, May (Mrs. Gustave) (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Lewis, Salim L. (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Newland, Charles A. (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Nichols, Alfred C., Jr. (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Rosen, Maurice M. (signed "Maury") (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Schenck, Edgar C. (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Trachtenberg, Rose (Mrs. Carl) (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Whelan, Grover (signed "Grover") (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Wright, Dickens (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Philanthropy/Awards/Engagement Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Bell, Jack (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Braun, John W. (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Edstrom, Ed (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Heir, Dorothy (Mrs. Milron) (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Horl, Ray (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Morris, Keith (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Mundin, Kathleen (Mrs. Herbert T.) (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Nash, Leslie (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Patterson, Richard C., Jr. (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Philippe, C.C. (signed "F") (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Ricciardi, Jack P. (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Rosenberg, Anna M. (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Zeitz, Abraham (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Philanthropy/Awards/Engagement Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Delehanty, Dorothea W. (Mrs. William E.) (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Feinman, Sylvia (Mrs. Max L.) (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Fine, Dorothy (signed "Dodey") (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Fish, Fred K. (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Howe, Buddy (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Zaslow, Jacqueline (signed "Jacky") (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Philanthropy/Awards/Engagement Correspondence, 1963-1969 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Cohen, Carol Ann (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Dennis, Walter L. (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Einiger, Glory (Mrs. Jack H.) (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Farkas, Ruth Lewis (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Garry, Janet T. (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Henry, Martha (Mrs. Jerome) (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Kleinschmidt, Madeline (Mrs. Frederick L.) (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Rowe, Joan (Mrs. Lee) (Box 1, Folder 34)
        Photocopy of original handwritten letter
      - Samuel. Ruth U. (Mrs. Sanford) (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Sarnoff, Lizette H. (Mrs. David) (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Philanthropy/Awards/Engagement Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Affinito, Lilyan H. (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Bartter, Scharlie W. (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Burden, Mrs. Marian (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Hertz, Miriam (Mrs. S. Clifford) (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Reed, Elizabeth (signed "Liz") (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Thomas, Louise (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Twentyman, Esther (Mrs. Gerald) (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - B. Contracts/Financial
    - Contracts 1940, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - American Federation of Radio Artists membership card, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Contracts, 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Contracts, 1950, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Contracts, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Contracts, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Contracts & misc, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Undated Contracts (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Career Related Financial (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - C. Awards
    - Certificate of Honor Red Cross - War Fund, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - New York City Cancer Committee Distinguished Service Award, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Commendation for cooperation at "Byline Ball" - Newspaper Reporters Association of New York City, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Department of Defense Certificate of Esteem (for USO shows), 1952 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - D. Programs, Billings, and Publicity Material
    - Programs/Publicity Material 1933-1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Programs/Publicity Material 1941 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Programs/Publicity Material, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Programs/Publicity Material, 1942 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Programs/Publicity Material, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Programs/Publicity Material, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Programs/Publicity Material, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Programs/Publicity Material, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Programs/Publicity Material, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Programs/Publicity Material, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Programs/Publicity Material, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Programs/Publicity Material, 1948 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Programs/Publicity Material, Jan 1949-Oct 1949 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Programs/Publicity Material, Nov 1949-Dec 1949 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Programs/Publicity Material, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Programs/Publicity Material, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Programs/Publicity Material, 1951 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Programs/Publicity Material, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Programs/Publicity Material, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Programs/Publicity Material, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 17)